https://www.proboards.com/privacy#cookies

Privacy Policy
Last Updated: March 31, 2020
This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") explains how ProBoards, Inc. ("ProBoards," "we," or "us") collects, uses, shares, and protects information of the users of the ProBoards.com website (the "Website"). This Privacy Policy is designed to fulfill our legal obligations in the places where we operate—including, without limitation and where applicable, the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and Canada's Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). Please note that this Privacy Policy only applies to the Website, and not to websites, applications, operating systems, or other platforms of third parties (collectively, "Third-Party Platforms"), even if such Third-Party Platforms are linked to or accessible from the Website. Each Third-Party Platform will have its own data collection and usage practices, and may use their own cookies, web beacons, and other technology to collect information from you. ProBoards is not responsible for the content or practices of any Third-Party Platforms and, if you choose to visit or use them, you do so at your own risk.
Who controls your information?
What types of information do we collect?
How and when do we collect information about you?
How do we use your information?
How do we share your information?
Do we sell your information to others?
How do we protect your information?
How long do we keep your information?
Do we transfer your information to a different country?
What are your rights when it comes to accessing, correcting, or deleting your information, and how can you exercise them?
How do we protect the privacy of children?
How can you receive and opt-out from marketing communications?
Do we respond to Do Not Track (DNT) Signals?
How will you know when we change the Privacy Policy?
How can you contact us regarding this Privacy Policy?
1. Who controls your information?
Any information or other data provided to or gathered by ProBoards is controlled by ProBoards, Inc., 26060 Towne Centre Drive, Foothill Ranch, California 92610, United States.
2. What types of information do we collect?
"Information," as used in this Privacy Policy, means personal information that identifies, relates to, describes, is reasonably capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular user or household. Examples include a user's name, mailing address, email address, or IP address.
ProBoards collects and/or has collected over the past twelve (12) months the following categories of information about you and other users of the Website:
Information You Provide to Us.
We collect information from you when you voluntarily provide it to us over the Website, including as part of registering a user
or ordering goods or services from ProBoards. Such information may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, telephone number(s), website URLs, your instant messaging screen names, your date of birth, street address, city, and/or state.
Content You Make Public.
The Website contains features that allow you to upload, post, transmit, display, perform or distribute content, including personal information about yourself. For example, you may choose to include personal information within your ProBoards profile, which is available and accessible to all visitors of the Website. Any information that you choose to disclose by means of such features becomes public information over which ProBoards is unable to exercise control. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information by means of such features.
Transaction and Payment Information.
All payments are processed by third-party vendors, such as Stripe. If you make any payment to ProBoards, we may send to these third-party vendors information related to the financial transaction, such as your credit or debit card information and billing address. ProBoards does not store or otherwise retain any credit or debit card information. However, we may gather non-payment information from you when you make a purchase through the Website or contact customer service regarding a prior transaction. Such information may include information regarding the subscriptions or services you purchased.
Device/Internet Connection Information.
When you use the Website, we automatically gather information made available by your web browser (such as Microsoft Edge or Google Chrome), internet service provider (such as Comcast or Cox), and device (such as your computer, phone, tablet, or fitness tracker), depending on your settings for each. For example, we may collect your IP address, information about the operating system or type of device you use, the device ID associated with your device, the date and time you access the Website, and your log in attempts.
Internet Activity Information.
As explained below in Sections 3 and 4 regarding Personalized Ads, we may also collect information about your browsing history, search history, and information regarding your interaction the Website. We may collect information regarding the websites, application, or advertisement you visited immediately before and after your use of the Website.
Geolocation Information.
We may collect information about where you are located, both generally and at the time you access the Website. For example, we may collect your billing address when you make a purchase, or ascertain your approximate location from your IP address.
Protected Class Information.
Due to the specific nature of ProBoards' services, you may be asked for your age or be given the option to provide information about your gender.
Other Information.
From time to time, we may collect other information from you, such as when you make a claim for a prize pursuant to a contest or other promotion run on the Website, when you request assistance through our customer service department, or when you voluntarily subscribe to promotions, reminders, or newsletters. You will always be asked for your consent in advance of providing such other information, and we will not collect it without your permission.
3. How and when do we collect information about you?
ProBoards gathers information about you through the following sources and means:
When you enter or upload information to the Website.
ProBoards collects information you provide to us, content you make public, transaction and payment information, geolocation information, and protected class information when you enter such information on a form on the Website (including during registration), purchase services, sign up for newsletters or promotional material, enter contests, upload content, post in a forum, and otherwise interact with the Website.
When you communicate with us.
ProBoards may also collect information you provide to us, content you make public, transaction and payment information, geolocation information, and protected class information, from you outside of the Website, such as when you contact our customer service department, email us (including any response to an email communication from ProBoards), or communicate with ProBoards via social media, such as by posting on a page hosted by ProBoards or tagging ProBoards in your own post. The information collected off the Website may be combined with that collected through the Website—for example, if you order a service from the Website and later call customer service about the order, the information collected in both interactions may be linked.
Through Cookies, tracking tools, and other automated technologies.
When you use any website, certain information can be automatically collected through technological means. When you access the Website, your web browser automatically sends us device and internet connection information and certain internet activity information as described in Section 2.
ProBoards also uses Cookies and web beacon technology to gather device and internet connection information, internet activity information, geolocation information, and biometric information. "Cookies" are files that are placed on your computer or other device by websites you visit. The primary purpose of a Cookie is to identify you as a unique user of the Website. ProBoards uses the following types of Cookies, some of which are placed by Third Parties, to customize your Internet experience, keep you logged into websites, remember your search terms, and advertise products or services to you:
Type of Cookie
Purpose of Cookie
Necessary
Necessary Cookies are essential in order for the Website to display and perform properly. Necessary Cookies are used to identify you, prevent security risks, and to allow you to perform -related functions.
Preferences
Preferences Cookies are used to store preferences set by you and each user for their , such as your language preferences. Preferences Cookies improve your experience using the Website.
Analytics and Performance
Analytics and Performance Cookies collect information on how you and other users interact with the Website. Often, this information is aggregated, as discussed in Section 4, and is used to improve the Website.
Advertising
We may also use Cookies and web beacons, including those placed by Third Parties such as Google, to deliver Personalized Ads that may be of interest to you. We may also use a web beacon in email messages sent to track your response. Cookies and web beacons also help us and our Third-Party advertising partners ensure you do not see the same advertisements over and over.
You can change your Cookie settings in your Internet browser (e.g., Chrome, Edge, Firefox). If you disable Cookies, some of the features of the Website may not function correctly. For more information, see allaboutcookies.org.
From Third Parties.
ProBoards may also collect the following types of information from Third Parties: transaction and payment information (such as when you have your payment information saved in your web browser); device/internet connection information; internet activity information; geolocation information; analytics information; and biometric information.
Like many websites, ProBoards uses Google services and Cookies to improve the Website and advertise to users like you, as described more fully below. As such, when you use the Website, your personal information may be shared with Google, and shared by Google with ProBoards. You can learn more about how Google uses Cookies, and how to manage your Cookie preferences in your Internet browser and revoke your consent to Personalized Ads, by visiting the Google Cookie Policy.
Pixels, tags, and Cookies may also be set by our Third Party advertising partners, which may track your online behavior, track ads shown to you, and provide Personalized Ads to you. Statistical identification or other non-cookie technologies may be used by third parties, and browser settings that block cookies may have no effect on such technologies. Data collected by third parties from a particular browser or device may be used with another computer or device that is linked to the browser or device on which such data was collected. Because advertising revenue is the sole source of monetization for the free services provided by ProBoards to you and other users of the Website, ProBoards considers these to be essential services.
You can view the list of our Third Party Partners.
Remember, you can change your Cookie settings in your Internet browser (e.g., Chrome, Edge, Firefox). For more information, see allaboutcookies.org. You can better learn about such Third-Party data collection and advertising practices, including how to revoke your consent to Personalized Ads, at the following websites:
Your Online Choices
NAI Opt-Out
YourAdChoices
Rubicon Opt-Out
4. How do we use your information?
ProBoards may use the information we've gathered from you or your device, including through Cookies and Third Parties, for the following purposes:
Business Purposes.
When ProBoards uses your information for a "Business Purpose," it means such use is reasonably necessary and proportionate to achieve an operational purpose of the ProBoards. The following are the Business Purposes for which we may use your information:
Business Purpose
Types of Information
For Security. ProBoards uses the information we collect from you and other users to detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, and to identify and prosecute those responsible for that activity. For example, we look at IP addresses to determine if they are on the "ban list" for a given forum, so that we can prevent access to the forum.
Information you provide to us; Transaction and Payment Information; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information
To Fulfill Your Orders. We use the information we collect from you to process your payments (through our third-party vendors as described above) and fulfill your orders.
Information you provide to us; Transaction and Payment Information; Device/Internet Connection Information; Geolocation Information;
To Improve the Website.
ProBoards uses the information we collect from you and other users to provide and improve the Website. We use information to debug and identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality of the Website. As explained above, we use Cookies,
including those placed by Third Parties, to gather statistical information that helps us understand how you and other users engage with the Website and improve its performance via technological development.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information;
To Personalize Your User Experience. We use information gathered from Cookies to authenticate your logins, determine whether you are logged in or not, to allow you to set personal preferences when using the Website, and to make it so you don't have to reenter the same information when you visit the Website several times within a short timeframe.
Information you provide to us; Transaction and Payment Information; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information
To Communicate with You. We use your information to personalize communication with you, and to respond to your requests regarding your purchases and information on our products and services. We also use your information to notify you of updates to the Terms or this Privacy Policy.
Information you provide to us
To Create Deidentified Aggregate Information. ProBoards may combine your information with that of other users to create "Aggregate Information"— namely, statistical information about all users or a subset thereof. Aggregate Information is pseudonymized and deidentified. In other words, Aggregate Information cannot be used to identify, relate to, describe, be capable of being associated with, or be linked, directly or indirectly, to a particular consumer, including you.
In turn, Aggregate Information may be used by ProBoards for the Business and Commercial Purposes listed herein.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information; Protected Class Information
Commercial Purposes.
When ProBoards uses your information for a "Commercial Purpose," it means such use is intended to advance ProBoards' business interests, such as by inducing you to buy one of our services. The following are the Commercial Purposes for which we may use your information:
Commercial Purpose
Types of Information
To Advertise to You. We may use information gathered through Cookies and web beacons, including those placed by Third Parties, to deliver ads to you via the Website, and after you've left the Website, including advertising specific to your personal interests. The purpose of this practice, which is sometimes called "Personalized Ads," "retargeting," or "remarketing" is to deliver content and advertising that is of interest to you, and to avoid displaying irrelevant advertising to you.
You can better learn about such ThirdParty data collection and advertising practices, including how to revoke your consent to Personalized Ads, at the following websites:
Your Online Choices
NAI Opt-Out
YourAdChoices
Rubicon Opt-Out
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information
To Advertise to Others. We may share your reviews, comments, and other content uploaded by you to advertise and market our Website and the Services, including by reposting your comments on the Website, in our advertising, or through our social media accounts.
Content you make public
Scope and Legal Bases for Use
ProBoards only processes your information to the extent that is necessary to accomplish the above-stated Business and Commercial Purposes, which serves as our legitimate interest.
If you reside in a location governed by the GDPR, then the following are ProBoards' legal bases for the processing of your information: In so far as we have obtained consent for processing operations of information by the data subject, Art. 6(1) lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis. For the processing of information necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is a party, Art. 6(1) lit. b GDPR serves as legal basis. The same applies to such processing operations which are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures. In so far as the processing of information is required to comply with a legal obligation to which our ProBoards is subject, Art. 6(1) lit. c GDPR serves as legal basis. In the event that processing of information may be necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person, Art. 6(1) lit. d GDPR serves as legal basis. If processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our ProBoards or by a Third Party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject, processing operations are based on Art 6 (1) lit. f GDPR
5. How do we share your information?
ProBoards may share your information with Third Parties for the following purposes:
Business Purposes.
When ProBoards shares your information for a Business Purpose, it means such use is reasonably necessary and proportionate to achieve an operational purpose of the ProBoards. The following are the Business Purposes for which we may share your information:
Third Parties
Business Purpose
Types of Information
Other Users. The Website contains features that allow you to upload, post, transmit, display, perform or distribute content, including personal information about yourself. Once you have chosen to divulge information about yourself to another user, multiple users, or the public at large through the Website— including in a "members-only" forum, direct message or otherwise—such information can be copied, transmitted or displayed by the recipient(s) and is no longer within ProBoards' ability to control.
To provide the Website and allow you and other users the opportunity to communicate via a forum.
Content you make public
Forum Administrators and Moderators. When you join, access, or post on a forum, information may be shared with other members that assist in running the forum, such as administrators or moderators.
To provide the Website and allow you and other users the opportunity to communicate via a forum.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Device/Internet Connection Information; Geolocation Information;
Service Providers. These Third Parties provide services to ProBoards that allow ProBoards to operate the Website, provide services to customers, communicate with customers, and so forth. Examples include payment processors, email fulfillment providers, customer management services, and so forth.
For Security; To Fulfill Your Orders; to Improve the Website, to Personalize Your User Experience; and to Create Aggregate Information. See Section 4 for more information on these Business Purposes.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Transaction and Payment Information; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information; Protected Class Information
Our Affiliated Entities. Affiliated entities are different than Third Parties in that they are businesses that are directly related to us and have common ownership with us. We may disclose, transfer, and sell your information to our affiliated entities, in which event, your information shall be treated by the affiliated companies in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Should Company be subject to an acquisition, merger,
or other change of control or business entity status, we reserve the right to transfer or assign your information as part of that acquisition, merger or .
For Security; To Fulfill Your Orders; to Improve the Website, to Personalize Your User Experience; and to Create Aggregate Information. See Section 4 for more information on these Business Purposes.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Transaction and Payment Information; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information; Protected Class Information
Government Officials and Private Parties Pursuant to Valid Legal Process. We may disclose your information in response to subpoenas, court orders, and other legal processes. In very rare circumstances, we may disclose personal information when we believe it is necessary in order to prevent illegal, fraudulent, or injurious actions that may cause harm to individuals.
To comply with ProBoards' legal obligations and to prevent illegal, fraudulent, or injurious actions that may cause harm to individuals.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Transaction and Payment Information; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information; Protected Class Information
Commercial Purposes.
When ProBoards shares your information for a "Commercial Purpose," it means such disclosure is intended to advance ProBoards' business interests, such as by advertising our products or services. The following are the Commercial Purposes for which we may share your information with Third Parties:
Commercial Purpose
Types of Information
Advertising Partners. We may disclose your personal information as needed to our Third-Party advertising partners.
To Advertise to You, including through Personalized Ads; to Advertise to Others. See Section 4 for more information on these Commercial Purposes.
Information you provide to us; Content you make public; Device/Internet Connection Information; Internet Activity Information; Geolocation Information
Forum Indexers.
As explained more fully in Section 6, ProBoards allows third-party Effyis, Inc. dba: BoardReader.com to index the public forums on the Website in exchange for a fee.
To promote the Website and create ease of access of Website content; to earn revenue.
Content you make public
Other Consumers. We may share your reviews, comments, and other content uploaded by you to advertise and market our Website and the Services, including by reposting your reviews on the Website, in our advertising, or through our social media accounts.
To Advertise to Others. See Section 4 for more information on this Commercial Purpose.
Content you make public
6. Do we sell your information to others?
Yes. Please take notice that your information may be sold to a Third Party. ProBoards has partnered with third-party Effyis, Inc. dba: BoardReader.com, a search engine that specializes in the indexing of public forum content. ProBoards allows BoardReader.com to index the public forums on the Website in exchange for a fee. The categories of information that may be indexed by BoardReader.com are:
Content you make public
RIGHT TO OPT-OUT OF
OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
You have the right, at any time, to direct ProBoards not to sell your information. You may do so by filling out the Do Not Sell My Personal Information form on the Website or emailing us at privacy@proboards.com.
7. How do we protect your information?
ProBoards has implemented and maintains reasonable security procedures and practices to protect against the unauthorized access, use or disclosure of your information. Among other things, we:
Host our servers with in secure data center facilities;
Use the services of Cloudflare to block DDoS attacks, bots, malicious traffic, and secure
our login systems with HTTPS/SSL;
Store passwords in a secure format, not plain text;
Use firewalls and a secure VPN to provide further security to our systems; and
Maintain a thorough Cyber Security Response Plan.
However, no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although we take steps to secure your information, we cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your personal and commercial information, or other communications, will always remain secure.
The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Never share your password with anyone else and notify us as soon as possible if you believe your
security has been breached.
8. How long do we keep your information?
ProBoards will retain your information for the length of time necessary to fulfill the Business Purposes and Commercial Purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law or valid court order. If you request deletion of your information pursuant to Section 10, your request will be processed according to the timeframes indicated therein and/or pursuant to any applicable legislation.
9. Do we transfer your information to a different country?
If you are visiting the Website from a location outside of the United States, your connection will be through and to servers located in the United States, and all information you provide will be processed and securely maintained in our web servers and internal systems located within the United States. By using the Website, you authorize and specifically consent to the transfer of personal data to the United States and its storage and use as specified above when you provide such information to us.
10. What are your rights when it comes to accessing, correcting, or deleting your information, and how can you exercise them?
You may access all information we've collected and retained about you for purposes of correcting, amending, downloading, or deleting such information. Access can be obtained by logging into your , making a Privacy Request, or contacting us at privacy@proboards.com.
To protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access, making corrections, providing you with information, or deleting information. Such verification will include requiring you to login to your
or, in the event you have forgotten your login credentials, completing the
reset process so that you may log into your .
Access and Correction
The easiest way to manage the content and information you share by logging into your . You can also download information associated with your ProBoards
by visiting your
Settings page. In the alternative, you may make a Privacy Request, or contact us at privacy@proboards.com.
Right to Request Disclosure
You have the right to request that ProBoards disclose the following to you:
The categories of personal information we have collected about you;
The categories of sources from which the personal information is collected;
The business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling personal information;
The categories of third parties with whom we share personal information; and
The specific pieces of personal information we have collected about you.
To request such a disclosure, please make a Privacy Request, or contact us at privacy@proboards.com.
Right to Request Deletion
You can delete your ProBoards
by visiting your
Settings page. You also have the right to request that ProBoards delete any personal information about you which we have collected from you. To make such a request, please make a Privacy Request, or contact us at privacy@proboards.com.
Please note that, when you share information in a forum, whether private or public, you are contributing to an online conversation or thread. In ProBoards' experience, threads are deprived of necessary context, and are sometimes rendered false or misleading, when select posts are altered or deleted after the fact. For this reason, except as required under California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 or similar law, ProBoards does not allow you to bulk delete your content from published posts. In addition, your ability to edit or delete your content may depend on forum-specific rules and settings designated by moderators or administrators, so you should think carefully about what you post before you do so.
California Shine the Light Disclosure
Under California's "Shine the Light" law, California residents who provide personal information to the Website may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please make a Privacy Request, or contact us at privacy@proboards.com.
Cal. Bus. & Prof. Code § 22581 Disclosure
If you are a California resident under the age of 18, and a registered user of any Website where this Privacy Policy is posted, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you to request and obtain removal of content or information you have publicly posted. To make such a request, please make a Privacy Request, or contact us at privacy@proboards.com with a detailed description of the specific content or information. Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal even if requested.
RIGHT TO OPT-OUT OF
OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
You have the right, at any time, to direct ProBoards not to sell your information as described in Section 6. You may do so by filling out the Do Not Sell My Personal Information form on the Website or emailing us at privacy@proboards.com.
11. How do we protect the privacy of children?
No Users Under 13
ProBoards will never knowingly collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database. Because we do not collect such information, we have no such information to use or to disclose to Third Parties. We have designed this policy in order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).
Right to Opt In For Users 13 to 16
ProBoards will never sell the personal information of users if we have actual knowledge that the user is less than 16 years of age, unless (in the case of consumers between 13 and 16 years of age) the user has affirmatively authorized the
of their personal information.
Cal. Bus. & Prof. Code § 22581 Disclosure
If you are a California resident under the age of 18, and a registered user of any Website where this Privacy Policy is posted, California Business and Professions Code Section 22581 permits you to request and obtain removal of content or information you have publicly posted. To make such a request, please make a Privacy Request, or contact us at privacy@proboards.com with a detailed description of the specific content or information. Please be aware that such a request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted and that there may be circumstances in which the law does not require or allow removal even if requested.
12. How can you receive and opt-out from marketing communications?
By providing your email address to ProBoards through the Website or an email initiated by you, you consent to receive emails from us, including information concerning your
and advertising messages. Depending upon your location, we may obtain additional consent from you via a checkbox disclosure or an email requesting confirmation before you can receive such information.
Providing consent to promotional emails is NOT a condition of purchasing any goods or services from ProBoards. You can unsubscribe to advertising emails at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link within the email. Please note that, even if you unsubscribe from advertising emails, we will still send you any necessary, non-promotional emails about your purchase, , or updates to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service.
13. Do we respond to Do Not Track (DNT) Signals?
DNT is a feature offered by some browsers which, when enabled, sends a signal to websites to request that your browsing is not tracked. ProBoards does not currently respond to DNT requests.
14. How will you know when we change the Privacy Policy?
Each time you use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Although most changes are likely to be minor, we reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy by posting such modification on this page; however, if changes are significant, we may provide a more prominent notice or email you. Depending upon your location, we may obtain additional consent from you via a checkbox disclosure, email, or personal message.
Unless we receive your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier version.
15. How can you contact us regarding this Privacy Policy?
The Website contains a Support Forum, which can be used for electronic contact. If you use this option, the data entered by you in the forum will be transmitted to us and stored as part of your information.
Alternatively, you can contact us via email at privacy@proboards.com. In this case, your information transmitted by email will be stored. If needed, your information will be relayed to our Third-Party partners to for the sole purpose of processing any request by you in the communication.
